 [
  {
    "numb": 1,
    "type": "Multiple Choices",
    "question": "What is the purpose of a file extension?",
    "answer": "B) To identify the type of file",
    "options": [
      "A) To compress the file",
      "B) To identify the type of file",
      "C) To encrypt the file",
      "D) To format the file"
    ]
  },
  {
    "numb": 2,
    "type": "Multiple Choices",
    "question": "Which of the following is an example of application software?",
    "answer": "C) Word Processor",
    "options": [
      "A) Operating System",
      "B) Utility Program",
      "C) Word Processor",
      "D) Device Driver"
    ]
  },
  {
    "numb": 3,
    "type": "Multiple Choices",
    "question": "What is the role of an operating system?",
    "answer": "B) To manage and coordinate activities within a computer",
    "options": [
      "A) To create new hardware",
      "B) To manage and coordinate activities within a computer",
      "C) To protect the computer from viruses",
      "D) To design software applications"
    ]
  },
  {
    "numb": 4,
    "type": "Multiple Choices",
    "question": "Which of the following is not a function of an operating system?",
    "answer": "C) Designing websites",
    "options": [
      "A) Interfacing with users",
      "B) Booting the computer",
      "C) Designing websites",
      "D) Managing network connections"
    ]
  },
  {
    "numb": 5,
    "type": "Multiple Choices",
    "question": "Which of the following is a method to enhance processing efficiency in operating systems?",
    "answer": "D) All of the above",
    "options": [
      "A) Buffering",
      "B) Virtual memory",
      "C) Multitasking",
      "D) All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "numb": 6,
    "type": "Multiple Choices",
    "question": "What does GUI stand for?",
    "answer": "A) Graphical User Interface",
    "options": [
      "A) Graphical User Interface",
      "B) General User Interface",
      "C) Graphic Utility Integration",
      "D) General Utility Interface"
    ]
  },
  {
    "numb": 7,
    "type": "Multiple Choices",
    "question": "What is the purpose of device drivers?",
    "answer": "B) To manage the interaction between hardware and the operating system",
    "options": [
      "A) To create new devices",
      "B) To manage the interaction between hardware and the operating system",
      "C) To design user interfaces",
      "D) To encrypt files"
    ]
  },
  {
    "numb": 8,
    "type": "Multiple Choices",
    "question": "What is multitasking?",
    "answer": "B) Running multiple programs simultaneously",
    "options": [
      "A) Running multiple operating systems simultaneously",
      "B) Running multiple programs simultaneously",
      "C) Running multiple threads in a single program",
      "D) None of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "numb": 9,
    "type": "Multiple Choices",
    "question": "What is virtual memory?",
    "answer": "C) Hard drive space used as additional RAM",
    "options": [
      "A) The physical memory installed in a computer",
      "B) A type of RAM",
      "C) Hard drive space used as additional RAM",
      "D) The main storage of the computer"
    ]
  },
  {
    "numb": 10,
    "type": "Multiple Choices",
    "question": "What does spooling stand for?",
    "answer": "B) Simultaneous Peripheral Operations On-Line",
    "options": [
      "A) Sequential Programming",
      "B) Simultaneous Peripheral Operations On-Line",
      "C) Special Program Operating Logic",
      "D) Sequential Peripheral Operations On-Line"
    ]
  },
  {
    "numb": 11,
    "type": "Multiple Choices",
    "question": "Which of the following uses a command-line interface?",
    "answer": "B) DOS",
    "options": [
      "A) Windows",
      "B) DOS",
      "C) Mac OS",
      "D) Linux"
    ]
  },
  {
    "numb": 12,
    "type": "Multiple Choices",
    "question": "Which operating system is known for its use in servers and workstations?",
    "answer": "C) UNIX",
    "options": [
      "A) Windows XP",
      "B) Mac OS",
      "C) UNIX",
      "D) Chrome OS"
    ]
  },
  {
    "numb": 13,
    "type": "Multiple Choices",
    "question": "What does PnP stand for in computing?",
    "answer": "A) Plug and Play",
    "options": [
      "A) Plug and Play",
      "B) Play and Pause",
      "C) Plug and Pause",
      "D) Print and Play"
    ]
  },
  {
    "numb": 14,
    "type": "Multiple Choices",
    "question": "Which operating system is open source and was developed by L.Torvalds?",
    "answer": "D) Linux",
    "options": [
      "A) Windows",
      "B) Mac OS",
      "C) UNIX",
      "D) Linux"
    ]
  },
  {
    "numb": 15,
    "type": "Multiple Choices",
    "question": "Which version of Windows introduced the Aero interface?",
    "answer": "C) Windows Vista",
    "options": [
      "A) Windows XP",
      "B) Windows 7",
      "C) Windows Vista",
      "D) Windows 8"
    ]
  },
  {
    "numb": 16,
    "type": "Multiple Choices",
    "question": "What is the primary function of a firewall?",
    "answer": "B) To protect against unauthorized access",
    "options": [
      "A) To store data",
      "B) To protect against unauthorized access",
      "C) To manage network connections",
      "D) To optimize storage space"
    ]
  },
  {
    "numb": 17,
    "type": "Multiple Choices",
    "question": "What does the term 'buffering' refer to in operating systems?",
    "answer": "B) Storing data temporarily",
    "options": [
      "A) Increasing processing speed",
      "B) Storing data temporarily",
      "C) Encrypting data",
      "D) Compressing files"
    ]
  },
  {
    "numb": 18,
    "type": "Multiple Choices",
    "question": "Which operating system is primarily designed for smartphones?",
    "answer": "C) Android",
    "options": [
      "A) Windows XP",
      "B) Mac OS",
      "C) Android",
      "D) Linux"
    ]
  },
  {
    "numb": 19,
    "type": "Multiple Choices",
    "question": "What is the role of a file management program?",
    "answer": "C) To organize and manage files and folders",
    "options": [
      "A) To create new files",
      "B) To manage the system's hardware",
      "C) To organize and manage files and folders",
      "D) To secure the computer"
    ]
  },
  {
    "numb": 20,
    "type": "Multiple Choices",
    "question": "Which of the following is a common feature in most operating systems today?",
    "answer": "B) Graphical user interface",
    "options": [
      "A) Command line interface",
      "B) Graphical user interface",
      "C) Manual memory management",
      "D) No multitasking"
    ]
  },
  {
    "numb": 21,
    "type": "Multiple Choices",
    "question": "Which of the following operating systems is known for being proprietary to Apple?",
    "answer": "B) Mac OS",
    "options": [
      "A) Windows",
      "B) Mac OS",
      "C) Linux",
      "D) UNIX"
    ]
  },
  {
    "numb": 22,
    "type": "Multiple Choices",
    "question": "What is a thread in the context of computing?",
    "answer": "B) A sequence of instructions within a program",
    "options": [
      "A) A type of computer virus",
      "B) A sequence of instructions within a program",
      "C) A method of file compression",
      "D) A type of user interface"
    ]
  },
  {
    "numb": 23,
    "type": "Multiple Choices",
    "question": "What is the primary purpose of utility programs?",
    "answer": "B) To perform specific tasks related to managing or maintaining the computer system",
    "options": [
      "A) To create new software applications",
      "B) To perform specific tasks related to managing or maintaining the computer system",
      "C) To design user interfaces",
      "D) To manage network connections"
    ]
  },
  {
    "numb": 24,
    "type": "Multiple Choices",
    "question": "Which operating system was dominant in the 1980s and early 1990s?",
    "answer": "C) DOS",
    "options": [
      "A) Windows",
      "B) Mac OS",
      "C) DOS",
      "D) UNIX"
    ]
  },
  {
    "numb": 25,
    "type": "Multiple Choices",
    "question": "What is the purpose of file compression programs?",
    "answer": "B) To reduce file size for storage and transmission",
    "options": [
      "A) To increase file size",
      "B) To reduce file size for storage and transmission",
      "C) To encrypt files",
      "D) To format files for printing"
    ]
  },
  {
    "numb": 26,
    "type": "Multiple Choices",
    "question": "What does the term 'multithreading' refer to?",
    "answer": "B) Executing multiple threads within a single program simultaneously",
    "options": [
      "A) Executing multiple programs simultaneously",
      "B) Executing multiple threads within a single program simultaneously",
      "C) Executing a single thread in a program",
      "D) Managing multiple files simultaneously"
    ]
  },
  {
    "numb": 27,
    "type": "Multiple Choices",
    "question": "Which operating system was developed by Microsoft Corporation?",
    "answer": "C) Windows",
    "options": [
      "A) Mac OS",
      "B) UNIX",
      "C) Windows",
      "D) Linux"
    ]
  },
  {
    "numb": 28,
    "type": "Multiple Choices",
    "question": "Which version of Windows was designed for both PCs and tablets?",
    "answer": "B) Windows 8",
    "options": [
      "A) Windows XP",
      "B) Windows 8",
      "C) Windows 7",
      "D) Windows 10"
    ]
  },
  {
    "numb": 29,
    "type": "Multiple Choices",
    "question": "Which of the following is not a type of operating system?",
    "answer": "C) Database management system",
    "options": [
      "A) Real-time operating system",
      "B) Multi-user operating system",
      "C) Database management system",
      "D) Distributed operating system"
    ]
  },
  {
    "numb": 30,
    "type": "Multiple Choices",
    "question": "What is the primary purpose of a system restore point?",
    "answer": "B) To return the system to a previous state",
    "options": [
      "A) To increase processing speed",
      "B) To return the system to a previous state",
      "C) To backup all data on the system",
      "D) To delete unnecessary files"
    ]
  },
  {
    "numb": 31,
    "type": "Multiple Choices",
    "question": "What is the role of a scheduler in an operating system?",
    "answer": "C) To manage the execution of processes",
    "options": [
      "A) To manage user files",
      "B) To design software applications",
      "C) To manage the execution of processes",
      "D) To protect the system from malware"
    ]
  },
  {
    "numb": 32,
    "type": "Multiple Choices",
    "question": "Which operating system is open source and based on UNIX?",
    "answer": "C) Linux",
    "options": [
      "A) Windows",
      "B) Mac OS",
      "C) Linux",
      "D) Android"
    ]
  },
  {
    "numb": 33,
    "type": "Multiple Choices",
    "question": "What is the purpose of disk cleanup?",
    "answer": "B) To remove unnecessary files and free up space",
    "options": [
      "A) To format the disk",
      "B) To remove unnecessary files and free up space",
      "C) To install a new operating system",
      "D) To encrypt the files on the disk"
    ]
  },
  {
    "numb": 34,
    "type": "Multiple Choices",
    "question": "What is the role of a hypervisor in virtualization?",
    "answer": "C) To manage virtual machines",
    "options": [
      "A) To create virtual networks",
      "B) To run applications on virtual machines",
      "C) To manage virtual machines",
      "D) To design software applications"
    ]
  },
  {
    "numb": 35,
    "type": "Multiple Choices",
    "question": "Which of the following is not a task of the operating system?",
    "answer": "D) Compiling code",
    "options": [
      "A) Memory management",
      "B) Process management",
      "C) File system management",
      "D) Compiling code"
    ]
  },
  {
    "numb": 36,
    "type": "Multiple Choices",
    "question": "What is the purpose of a swap file?",
    "answer": "B) To extend the physical memory onto the hard drive",
    "options": [
      "A) To store backup data",
      "B) To extend the physical memory onto the hard drive",
      "C) To increase processing speed",
      "D) To manage user files"
    ]
  },
  {
    "numb": 37,
    "type": "Multiple Choices",
    "question": "What is the role of a bootloader in a computer system?",
    "answer": "C) To load the operating system into memory",
    "options": [
      "A) To create backups",
      "B) To encrypt the hard drive",
      "C) To load the operating system into memory",
      "D) To manage user accounts"
    ]
  },
  {
    "numb": 38,
    "type": "Multiple Choices",
    "question": "Which of the following is a characteristic of a real-time operating system (RTOS)?",
    "answer": "B) Fast processing of time-critical tasks",
    "options": [
      "A) High-level user interface",
      "B) Fast processing of time-critical tasks",
      "C) Built-in graphical design tools",
      "D) Large file management capacity"
    ]
  },
  {
    "numb": 39,
    "type": "Multiple Choices",
    "question": "What is the primary purpose of a task manager?",
    "answer": "B) To monitor and manage running processes",
    "options": [
      "A) To design user interfaces",
      "B) To monitor and manage running processes",
      "C) To secure the computer from viruses",
      "D) To manage user accounts"
    ]
  },
  {
    "numb": 40,
    "type": "Multiple Choices",
    "question": "Which of the following is a type of system software?",
    "answer": "A) Device driver",
    "options": [
      "A) Device driver",
      "B) Word processor",
      "C) Spreadsheet program",
      "D) Web browser"
    ]
  },
  {
    "numb": 41,
    "type": "Multiple Choices",
    "question": "What is the purpose of defragmentation?",
    "answer": "B) To optimize the layout of files on a disk",
    "options": [
      "A) To encrypt files",
      "B) To optimize the layout of files on a disk",
      "C) To increase network speed",
      "D) To format a hard drive"
    ]
  },
  {
    "numb": 42,
    "type": "Multiple Choices",
    "question": "Which of the following is a real-time operating system?",
    "answer": "D) RTOS",
    "options": [
      "A) DOS",
      "B) Linux",
      "C) Windows 10",
      "D) RTOS"
    ]
  },
  {
    "numb": 43,
    "type": "Multiple Choices",
    "question": "What does the term 'booting' refer to?",
    "answer": "B) Starting up a computer",
    "options": [
      "A) Creating a backup",
      "B) Starting up a computer",
      "C) Installing software",
      "D) Shutting down a computer"
    ]
  },
  {
    "numb": 44,
    "type": "Multiple Choices",
    "question": "What is the function of the kernel in an operating system?",
    "answer": "A) Manage hardware resources",
    "options": [
      "A) Manage hardware resources",
      "B) Provide a user interface",
      "C) Encrypt files",
      "D) Manage web browsers"
    ]
  },
  {
    "numb": 45,
    "type": "Multiple Choices",
    "question": "What is the primary use of a command-line interface?",
    "answer": "C) Executing text-based commands",
    "options": [
      "A) Web browsing",
      "B) File management",
      "C) Executing text-based commands",
      "D) Graphical design"
    ]
  },
  {
    "numb": 46,
    "type": "Multiple Choices",
    "question": "What is the purpose of an antivirus program?",
    "answer": "B) To detect and remove malicious software",
    "options": [
      "A) To increase processing speed",
      "B) To detect and remove malicious software",
      "C) To optimize storage space",
      "D) To create a duplicate copy of files"
    ]
  },
  {
    "numb": 47,
    "type": "Multiple Choices",
    "question": "What is the role of the BIOS in a computer system?",
    "answer": "B) Initialize and test hardware during the boot process",
    "options": [
      "A) Manage user accounts",
      "B) Initialize and test hardware during the boot process",
      "C) Design user interfaces",
      "D) Encrypt data"
    ]
  },
  {
    "numb": 48,
    "type": "Multiple Choices",
    "question": "Which of the following is not a type of system software?",
    "answer": "D) Spreadsheet program",
    "options": [
      "A) Operating system",
      "B) Utility software",
      "C) Firmware",
      "D) Spreadsheet program"
    ]
  },
  {
    "numb": 49,
    "type": "Multiple Choices",
    "question": "What is the role of a task manager in an operating system?",
    "answer": "B) To display and manage running applications and processes",
    "options": [
      "A) To manage user files",
      "B) To display and manage running applications and processes",
      "C) To design software applications",
      "D) To secure the computer from viruses"
    ]
  },
  {
    "numb": 50,
    "type": "Multiple Choices",
    "question": "Which operating system was designed for use in IBM-compatible PCs?",
    "answer": "C) Windows",
    "options": [
      "A) Mac OS",
      "B) UNIX",
      "C) Windows",
      "D) Linux"
    ]
  }
]